A Guide to the Scervant Jones Papers, 1834-1854
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Scervant Jones Papers, 1834-1854.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 76.2
39 items.
Jones, Scervant, 1785-1854.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1976.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm M-1317.2.
Biographical/Historical Information
Rev. Scervant Jones (1785-1854), son of John and Mary Hubard Jones. Jones was a lawyer, delegate from York County, Va., to the Virginia General Assembly (1822-1825), and first minister of the Williamsburg, Va., Baptist Church (1829-1854).
Scope and Content Information
Letters, will, and sermons of the Rev. Scervant Jones. The letters (1847-1851) are mostly from Jones, in Williamsburg, to Thomas B. Montague in Gloucester, Va. A copy of Jones's will, December 1852, is contained within an 1854 letter from Robert Saunders [of Williamsburg] to Montague. The twenty-seven sermons were written by Jones between 1834 and 1845 and most were preached in Williamsburg. Names appearing in the collection are Dr. Griffin, Bourbon Jones, William Jones, Dr. Charles Minnigerode, Sarah Ann Montague, Thomas B. Montague, Elisha Pollard, George Pollard, Sheldon and Maupin, and the College of William and Mary.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Each series is arranged chronologically.
Organization
The collection is divided into two series. The first series consists of correspondence. The second series consists of sermons.
Index Terms
Persons:
Jones, Scervant, 1785-1854.; Montague, Thomas B.; Saunders, Robert, 1805-1869.
Subjects:
Sermons, American--19th century.
Genre and Form Terms:
Estate records--Virginia.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1847-1854. (Folder 1-2)
  - S. Jones to T. B. Montague, Gloucester, 4 October 1847. (Folder 1)
  - S. Jones, Williamsburg, to T. B. Montague, Gloucester, 2 June 1848. (Folder 1)
  - S. Jones, Williamsburg, to T. B. Montague, Gloucester, 5 October 1849. (Folder 1)
  - S. Jones, Willliamsburg, to T. B. Montague, Gloucester, 17 October 1849. (Folder 1)
  - Wm. S. Jones, Shelly, Warwick County, to Elder Scervant Jones, Williamsburg, 3 May 1850. (Folder 1)
  - S. Jones, Williamsburg, to T. B. Montague, 6 May 1850. (Folder 1)
  - S. Jones, Williamsburg, to T. B. Montague, Gloucester, 17 June 1850. (Folder 1)
  - S. Jones, Williamsburg, to T. B. Montague, Gloucester, 4 October 1850. (Folder 2)
  - S. Jones, Williamsburg, to T. B. Montague, Gloucester, 5 October 1850. (Folder 2)
  - S. Jones, Williamsburg, to T. B. Montague, Gloucester, 31 July 1851. (Folder 2)
  - S. Jones, Williamsburg, to T. B. Montague, Gloucester, 29 August 1851. (Folder 2)
  - Robert Saunders, Williamsburg, to Thomas B. Montague, 8 May 1854. (Folder 2)
  - Copy of the will of Scervant Jones, 25 December 1852. (Folder 2)
- Sermons, 1834-1845. (Folder 3-5)
  - Sermon. "The final Judgement", 20 July 1834., 8 pages. (Folder 3)
    Preached in Williamsburg, Sunday morning July 20th 1834.
  - Sermon. "Are we Christians indeed?" 1834., 12 pages. (Folder 3)
    Preached at Williamsburg, 1834; Petsworth in Gloucester, 1835; Denbeigh in Warwick, 1836;and Williamsburg, Lord's Day morning August, 1844.
  - Sermon. "Holy Provocation," 1836., 4 pages. (Folder 3)
    Preached at Williamsburg, September, 1836.
  - Sermon. "Persuasives to Prayer," 1836., 8 pages. (Folder 3)
    Preached at Williamsburg, 1836; Grafton in 1838; Williamsburg, 1839.
  - Sermon. "On Neutrality," 1836., 4 pages. (Folder 3)
    Preached at Williamsburg, August, 1836 and March, 1839; Matthews 1840.
  - Sermon. "The Solemn Day," 1836., 4 pages. (Folder 3)
    Preached at Williamsburg, Lordsday morning, 1836; Pine Top Middlesex, Lordsday morning, 1837; Chickahominy, October, 1843.
  - Sermon. "On Preaching Christ and not Ourselves," 1836., 6 pages. (Folder 3)
    Preached at Williamsburg in 1836.
  - Sermon. "A Contrast of Different Characters," 1837., 4 pages. (Folder 3)
  - Sermon. No. 41 "The Instances, the Evil Nature and the Dangerous Tendency of Delay in the Concern of Religion," 1837., 4 pages. (Folder 3)
    Williamsburg, 1837.
  - Sermon. "On Reprobation," 1838., 8 pages. (Folder 4)
    Preached at Williamsburg, 1838; Peckatone, King & Queen Co., 1841; Cheescake, June, 1842.
  - Sermon. "Zeal for the Salvation of Sinners," 1839., 8 pages. (Folder 4)
    Preached at Williamsburg, January, 1839.
  - Sermon. "Sons of God," 1839., 8 pages. (Folder 4)
    Preached at Williamsburg, 1839.
  - Sermon. "Obedience Enforced," 1840., 4 pages. (Folder 4)
    Preached at the HW House in 1840.
  - Sermon. "Sin and its Cure," 1840., 4 pages. (Folder 4)
    Williamsburg, 1840.
  - Sermon. "The Sinner will not have Christ," 1840., 4 pages. (Folder 4)
    Preached at Williamsburg, 1840.
  - Sermon. "Love to God," 1840., 8 pages. (Box 4)
  - Sermon. "The Boaster Reproved," 1841., 4 pages. (Folder 4)
    Preached at Williamsburg, 1841.
  - Sermon. "The Sinner Man and his doom awful," 1842., 8 pages. (Folder 4)
    Preached at Williamsburg, Lordsday afternoon, November 13, 1842.
  - Sermon. "Baptism a positive Divine Institution," 1 April 1843., 20 pages. (Folder 5)
    Preached at Williamsburg, Lordsday morning, April 1, 1843 (The Funeral of Young Bro. Js. Johson and the administration of the Lords supper).
  - Sermon. "All Commanded to Work," 30 July 1843., 8 pages. (Folder 5)
    Preached at Williamsburg, Lordsday, July 30, 1843. Same August, 1845.
  - Sermon. "The World to come," 14 January 1844., 12 pages. (Folder 5)
    Preached at Williamsburg, Lordsday evening, January 14, 1844.
  - Sermon. "The Sanctuary," May 1844., 8 pages. (Folder 5)
    Preached at Cheescake, Lordsday morning, May, 1844.
  - Sermon. "Alarm to all Hearers," 6 July 1845., 4 pages. (Folder 5)
    Preached at Williamsburg, Lordsday evening, July 6, 1845.
  - Sermon. "On Righteousness," 17 August 1845., 8 pages. (Folder 5)
    Preached at Williamsburg, Lordsday evening, August 17, 1845.
  - Sermon. "The Cross of Christ," 19 August 1845., 4 pages. (Folder 5)
    Preached at Williamsburg, Tuesday evening, August 19, 1845.
  - Sermon. "Reasons for attending public worship," August 1845., 8 pages. (Folder 5)
    Preached at Williamsburg, Lordsday evening, August, 1845.
  - Sermon. "O Lord, revive they work in the midst of the years ...," n.d., 38 pages. (Folder 5)